(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
8周年記念LIVE 重大発表
[On-screen: 8th Anniversary Live - Major Announcement]
もうどうなってもいいや
作詞・作曲：須田景凪
I Don't Care Anymore
Lyrics & Composition: Keina Suda
堂々巡りのファンタジー アンソロジー
A roundabout fantasy anthology,
ナゾル謎謎
Mystery and mystery,
本能のままに行動
I’m acting on instinct,
鼓動に高まる衝動
The impulse that rises to the beat of my heart.
もうどうなってもいいや
I don’t care anymore...
当たり前の事が知りたいだけ
I just want to know the obvious things,
星に願う本当の気持ち
what I really wish for the stars.
苦し紛れの言い訳は
No more excuses for my anguish,
いらない 意味ない キミはどう思う??
It’s pointless, it’s meaningless, what do you think??
行き場を失ったみたいだ
It’s like I’ve lost my way,
心は棘の類で
my heart is a thorn in my side.
同じことばかり繰り返して
It’s just the same old thing over and over again,
鳥籠の中で踊る
dancing in a birdcage.
弱って穿って 取り繕うまで
Weak and pierced, till it’s mended,
足掻いて 泣き叫んで 消えないように
struggling and crying, trying not to disappear.
魔法みたいな都合いいもの
Something as convenient as magic,
主人公なら起承転結
if you’re the hero, there’s a beginning and an end.
最後はどうなってもHappy Ending
No matter what happens in the end, it’s always a Happy Ending,
それなら好きにさせてよ
then let me do what I want.
もうどうなってもいいや
I don’t care anymore.
真っ逆さまに落ちていった
I fell headlong into
無重力Midnight 逃避行
a zero-gravity Midnight escape.
秘密の裏側交わって虜
The secret behind the secret, I’m a prisoner of it.
一切合切持っていって
Take it all with you,
余すことなく人生謳歌
celebrating life with everything I’ve got.
混じり合う星に思い馳せて
Thinking of the stars mingling together,
月が綺麗だなんて
someone says “The moon is beautiful” [I love you],
この夜は全てWonder 愛を歌う
this night is all Wonder, singing of love.
もうどうなってもいいや
I don’t care anymore.
曖昧な笑顔に揺れてる
I’m swaying to your vague smile,
キミの瞳の奥へとピント合わしてFocus
focus on the depths of your eyes.
誰の触れたこともない真実の園
The garden of truth that no one has ever touched,
雨に濡れたカラダ ざわつく ぎらつく
body soaked in the rain, rustling, jittery,
簡単じゃないから もっと もっと もっと もっと 盲目に
because it’s not easy, more, more, more, more, blindly.
狂ってブワッと 曝け出すように
I’m going crazy, as if exposing everything,
1, 2の3でココロ Life Full
one, two, three in my heart, Life Full.
魔法みたいな都合いいもの
Something as convenient as magic,
そんなもんだって縋りつきたい
I want to put my trust in something like that.
諦めちゃってはもうBad Ending
Giving up is already a Bad Ending,
なけなしの勇気を もうどうなってもいいや
what little courage I have, I don’t care anymore.
火花みたいに燃えた証
The proof that burned like a spark,
いつの日か忘れちゃって
someday I’ll forget it.
「儚いね」なんて 感情の栞はさんで
“It’s so fragile,” putting a bookmark between my emotions,
特別になるんだろう
it will become special, won’t it?
真っ当では受け流されて
My feelings are just passed over if they're normal...
無重力Midnight 逃避行
Zero gravity Midnight escape
温もり感じる距離まで引き寄せて
Pulling you close enough to feel your warmth
月の涙が降った
Moonlight tears fell
この世はまるでStranger
This world is just like a Stranger
愛を叫ぶ
Shouting out my love
ビビデバ
[Song Title: Bibideba]
つまらないデイズもう散々ね！
Boring days, I've had enough!
奇蹟願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles
WATCH ME DO...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Occult secrets, magic with no tricks
I WANNA BE FREE！
I WANNA BE FREE!
だってまだふりだし
Since I'm still at the start
(THE PARTY AIN'T STARTED)
HEYタクシー ちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, take me to space
秒針は音を立てて
The second hand makes a sound
夜を急かす魔物のよう
Like a monster hurrying the night
人生は一瞬にして
Life, in an instant,
溶ける魔法
Is a magic that melts away
それならば駆け抜けて
In that case, run through it
想通り！
Just as you imagined!
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って
Jump onto the precocious carriage
DRIVIN'
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm a great transformation makeup!
我儘のまにまに
Going with my selfishness
燦きに注意
Watch out for the sparkle
洒落な街で
In a stylish town
DANCIN'
左様なら グッバイ劣等感
Farewell, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは 喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, cheers and claps from the audience
皆皆 御唱和あれ！
Everyone, sing along!
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
混絡がっても仕様が無い
It's no use if things get tangled
ガラスシューズで踊るTONIGHT
Dancing in glass shoes TONIGHT
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
今夜に明日など無いならば
If there's no tomorrow for tonight
自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
The winner is the one who dances freely, right?
DANCE！
DANCE!
ラリラリホ
Lali Lali Ho
どんな問題も解は一つ
Every problem has one solution
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す
I love blanks, correct answers, and mistakes too
本当のあたしの理想
The real ideal me
何だか世界は限界の気配がして
Somehow it feels like the world is at its limit
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just feeling safe makes me worried
今すぐJUMPIN OUT
Jumping out right now
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
CHITTY BANG BANG
唯唯諾諾に危機感抱く
Feeling a sense of crisis in being a yes-man
日々にぎりぎり爆発気味
On days when I'm just about to explode
たった今発散してしまおうか
Shall I vent it all right now?
まだまだビイビイ弾巧みに乱射
Still skillfully firing BB pellets
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ
One shot isn't enough
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally found the answer for you
灰に成る迄踊って居よう
Let's keep dancing until we turn to ash
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って
Jump onto the precocious carriage
DRIVIN'
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm a great transformation makeup!
我儘のまにまに
Going with my selfishness
燦きに注意
Watch out for the sparkle
洒落な街で
In a stylish town
DANCIN'
左様なら グッバイ劣等感
Farewell, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは 喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, cheers and claps from the audience
皆皆 御唱和あれ！
Everyone, sing along!
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
混絡がっても仕様が無い
It's no use if things get tangled
ガラスシューズで踊るTONIGHT
Dancing in glass shoes TONIGHT
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
今夜に明日など無いならば
If there's no tomorrow for tonight
自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
The winner is the one who dances freely, right?
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ということで、2曲お届けさせていただきました。
So, I've performed two songs for you.
皆さん楽しんでますかー！？
Is everyone having fun!?
今回は全編アコースティック編成ということで、
This time, it's a full acoustic arrangement,
今までの生誕ライブにはないしっとりとしたね、テイストでお送りしていこうと思いますよ。
so I'm going to present it with a calm taste that hasn't been in my birthday lives before.
8周年の感謝の気持ちを込めて、
With feelings of gratitude for the 8th anniversary,
じっくりと音楽に浸ってもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could fully immerse yourselves in the music.
それでは次の曲聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
「月に向かって撃て」！
"Tsuki ni mukatte ute"!
月に向かって撃て
[Song Title: Tsuki ni mukatte ute]
[Song: Shoot for the Moon]
眺めているばかり
Just staring at it,
手を伸ばして思い出す
reaching out and remembering.
聞かれたくない弱音
Complaints I don't want heard,
聴かせたい声
a voice I want you to hear.
不可能も可能性だ
Even the impossible is a possibility.
君が誰なんだか知ってんだ
I know who you are.
証明しよう 僕ら
Let's prove it—us,
本当はどうしたい？
what do we really want to do?
逃げたいと耳塞いだ
I covered my ears, wanting to run,
しゃがむ心臓を叩いてった
beating my cowering heart.
Swing by 変わらない表情に
Swing by, upon that unchanging expression,
答えを突き立てて
thrust an answer.
情熱は月に向かって撃て スナイパー
Shoot your passion at the moon, sniper.
未来はどうやら君次第
It seems the future is up to you.
喉が渇いたって後悔はないわ
Even if my throat goes dry, I've no regrets.
擦りむいて埋めるの99%
Filling that 99% with scrapes.
小指には衝動を
An impulse on my pinky,
本当はどうしたいんだっけ
what was it I really wanted to do?
合図して ハートチューンに乗せて
Give the signal, set it to the Heart Tune.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
一番乗りで Fly me to the moon
Being the first one there, fly me to the moon.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
ぶつかった壁も
The walls I hit,
ぶつけあった悔しさも
and the frustrations we clashed with.
不器用に照らすロゼッタになれ
Become the Rosetta that clumsily lights the way.
もしも人生が10分なら
If life were only ten minutes,
7分はあなたとの決着に
I'd spend seven settling things with you.
胸躍るようなアトラクションで Touch Down！！
With a heart-pounding attraction, touch down!!
臆病も“好き”で燃やしていけ スラスター
Burn away cowardice with "love," thrusters.
まだ見ぬゴールは君次第
The goal yet unseen is up to you.
夢も照らし合った公転軌道上
On an orbital path where dreams lit each other,
吸い込んで一息99%
inhale a breath at 99%.
雨音も喝采へ
Even the sound of rain becomes applause,
本当はどうしたいんだっけ
what was it I really wanted to do?
追いつくわ ハートチューンに賭けて
I'll catch up, betting on the Heart Tune.
証明しよう 届くんだって
Let's prove it—that we can reach.
情熱は月に向かって撃て スナイパー
Shoot your passion at the moon, sniper.
未来は今日も僕ら次第
Today too, the future is up to us.
誰が笑ったって後悔はないわ
No matter who laughs, I've no regrets.
擦りむいて埋めるの99%
Filling that 99% with scrapes.
小指には衝動を
An impulse on my pinky,
本当はどうしたいんだっけ
what was it I really wanted to do?
合図して ハートチューンに乗せて
Give the signal, set it to the Heart Tune.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
一番乗りで Fly me to the moon
Being the first one there, fly me to the moon.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
飛び込んできて Fly me to the moon
Dive right in, fly me to the moon.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
あなただけに Fly me to the moon
Just for you, fly me to the moon.
Ah, ah Darlin' I know who you are. Ah, Ah
綺麗事
[Song: Lip Service]
綺麗事を吐くその口が
Because the mouth that vomits lip service
君の事を苦しめるから
is what makes you suffer.
同じことばかりの日々に ああ
In these days that are always the same, ah,
意味を求めて寄り添い合うの
we huddle together seeking meaning.
ひしめき合うカラーフィルターの奥で笑ってる
Laughing from behind crowded color filters.
散々恨んだ狡猾さが 今、
That cunning I hated so much is now,
自分なりの生き方なのに
my own way of living, and yet,
潔癖な思考に縛られたままで
I remain bound by fastidious thoughts.
強がるくせに唇を噛む
Biting my lip while acting tough,
分かってない素振りをしてばかり
always pretending not to understand.
綺麗事を吐くその口が嫌いだから
Because I hate that mouth vomiting lip service,
歌を歌うんだ
I sing this song.
諦めているその顔が
That face that's giving up
僕の事を曇らせる
is what clouds my vision.
こんな声だって伝わらなくて
Even a voice like this won't get through,
もっと完璧な言葉を紡ぎたくて
I want to spin more perfect words.
ずっと欲張って きっと間違えて
Always being greedy, surely making mistakes,
今日も転げ落ちる 不完全な朝
falling down again today, an incomplete morning.
綺麗事
[Title: Kireigoto]
本音も言えない日常にはただ
In a daily life where I can't even say my true feelings
「理想なんて」と嘲け笑う声
Just voices mocking "ideals"
言い返す言葉も選べずに
Without even being able to choose words to retort
ただ増していく痛み
The pain just keeps increasing
虚勢を張る衝動で隠して
Hiding it with the impulse to bluster
綺麗なままで生きてたいのか
Do you want to keep living while being beautiful?
諦めを塗り重ねて
Painting over the resignation
「本当」が見えなくなってしまうんだ
The "truth" disappears
綺麗事を吐くその口が
The mouth that speaks of pretty things
綺麗事を吐くその口が(ah)
The mouth that speaks of pretty things (ah)
綺麗事を吐くその口が
The mouth that speaks of pretty things
嫌いだから歌を歌うんだ
I hate it, that's why I sing
諦めているその顔が
That resigned face of yours
君の事を苦しめる
Makes you suffer
こんな声だって伝わらなくて
Even these voices can't be conveyed
もっと完璧な言葉を紡ぎたくて
I want to weave even more perfect words
ずっと欲張ってきっと間違えて
Always greedy, surely making mistakes
それでも歌おう
Still, let's sing
不完全だから
Because I'm incomplete
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
楽しんでますか？
Are you enjoying yourselves?
さあ、みんなね、武道館「再演」で出したあの重大発表のティザー
So, everyone, that major announcement teaser we showed at the Budokan "SAIEN"...
あの内容が気になっている頃なのではないでしょうか？
...you must be wondering about what it's all about by now, right?
それから、みんなもちろん見つけてくれましたよね？
And of course, you all found it, didn't you?
先週の月曜日から、ある場所で屋外広告もね、出ていたりして
Since last Monday, outdoor advertisements have been appearing in certain places...
きっと今頃「何が起きるんだ」って、ただならぬ空気を見なさん感じて
...by now, I'm sure you're all feeling a strange atmosphere, wondering "What's going to happen?"...
どぎまぎしているんじゃないかなと思うんですけれども
...and feeling a bit flustered.
まずはね、言葉じゃなくて、今日の告知に向けて
But first, instead of words, heading towards today's announcement...
音楽に込めてみんなに伝えたいなと思い、こういう編成で今回やらせてもらっております
...I wanted to convey it through music, so we're performing with this setup today.
アコースティックってさ、なんかエモくて
Acoustic music, you know, it's kind of "emo"...
今までのことをこう思い返すような、なんかノスタルジックな気持ちになったりしますよね
...it makes you feel nostalgic, like you're looking back on everything that's happened.
いつもはテンションを上げてくれるあの曲が
Those songs that usually pump you up...
今日はまた違った形でみんなに響いたらいいなと思って歌わせていただいております
...I'm singing them today hoping they'll resonate with you in a different way.
楽曲のアレンジもそうだし、この生誕配信自体もそうだし
Whether it's the song arrangements or this birthday stream itself...
新しい一面を見せながらも、何よりこの8年間みんなで一緒にやってきた
...while showing a new side of myself, more than anything, these past 8 years we've spent together...
紡いできた絆みたいなものがしっかり感じられるライブにできたら嬉しいです
...I hope to make this a live where you can really feel the bond we've woven.
それでは次の曲に行きましょう
Now then, let's move on to the next song.
ムーンライト
Moonlight.
[Title: Moonlight]
遠くまで歩こうよ、裸足で
Let's walk far, barefoot
小さな幸せを見つけて
Find small happiness
湿った月が窓を覗いて
A wet moon peeks into the window
こっちへおいでと笑った
And laughed at me, saying "come here"
似たもの同士なんだよね、案外
We are similar people, surprisingly
分かり合えない部分も安牌
Unspoken parts are also safe bets
月明かりをめくった残像
An afterglow after flipping through moonlight
誰かにとっての普通をしよう
Let's do what's normal for someone
私と踊ってよ、ムーンライト
Dance with me, Moonlight
ねえ、こっちであそぼう サニーサイド
Hey, let's play here, Sunny Side
隠し事ばっかのインサイド
Inside, full of secrets
ねえ、こっちであそぼうよ ミッドナイト
Hey, let's play here, Midnight
この、メロウな今日をずっと泳いでいこう
Let's keep swimming through this mellow today
街明かりを奪って、月で待ち合わせ
Stealing the city lights, let's meet at the moon
届きそうで届かない、あなたはムーンライト
Seemingly reachable but not, you are the moonlight
理由もなく、寂しい夜が来て
For no reason, a lonely night comes
旧くなっていく記憶の上で眠りたい
I want to sleep on top of memories that are growing old
似たもの同士なんだから、厄介
Since we're two of a kind, it's troublesome
隠し事すらも抱えて、厄介
Even carrying secrets, it's troublesome
まだ、やることばっかで忙しいけどおやすみ
Still busy with nothing but things to do, but goodnight
あの、光の方へ どこか遠い方へ
Toward that light, somewhere far away
この、メロウな今日をずっと泳いでいこう
Let's keep swimming through this mellow today
尽きない悩みの種、話を聞かせて
The endless seeds of worry, let me hear your story
私とあなただけの世界で
In a world for only you and me
あの、一等星になって
Becoming that first-magnitude star
街をハイジャックしようぜ
Let's hijack the city
この、メロウな今日をずっと泳いでいこう
Let's keep swimming through this mellow today
穴だらけの心で、あなただけを思って
With a heart full of holes, thinking only of you
眠れそうで眠れない、こんな夜は
Seemingly able to sleep but unable, on a night like this
私と踊ってよ、ムーンライト
Dance with me, Moonlight
ねぇ、こっちであそぼう サニーサイド
Hey, let's play over here, on the sunny side
隠し事ばっかのインサイド
Inside is full of nothing but secrets
ねぇ、こっちであそぼうよ ミッドナイト
Hey, let's play over here, at midnight
街明かりを奪って、月で待ち合わせ
Stealing the city lights, let's meet at the moon
届きそうで届かない、あなたはムーンライト
Seemingly reachable but not, you are the moonlight
実はここからスペシャルゲストに来てもらっています。
Actually, I have a special guest joining us from here.
さあ、誰かわかるかな？
Now, do you know who it is?
それでは呼んじゃいましょう。
Then, let's call him out.
イノタクさーん！
Inotaku-san!
お久しぶりです。
It's been a while.
改めてよろしくお願いします。
Looking forward to working with you again.
来てくれて嬉しいです。
I'm happy you came.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ここからはイノタクさんにも入ってもらって、
From here on, Inotaku-san will also join us,
さらなる特別編成で何曲か続けてお届けしていきますよ。
and we'll deliver a few more songs in an even more special arrangement.
イノタクさん、準備はいいですか？
Inotaku-san, are you ready?
よろしくお願いします。
Yes, let's do it.
それでは聴いてください。
Then, please listen.
夜を待つよ。
Yoru wo Matsu yo.
夜を待つよ
[Title: Yoru wo Matsu yo]
夜を待つよ 夜を待つよ
Waiting for the night, waiting for the night
夜を待つよ 待つのよ
Waiting for the night, I'm waiting
今日もまたばっちりしっかりきまってる
Today again, I'm perfectly, firmly set
君ははっきりきっぱり歌ってる
You are clearly, decisively singing
明けない夜は
A night that never ends...
そんなものはないよと
"There's no such thing," you say
椰子の木がゆっくりゆっくりそよいでる
Palm trees are slowly, slowly swaying
ぼくはやっぱりさっぱりわかんない
I, after all, don't understand it at all
ただひたすらに
Just single-mindedly...
夜を待つよ
I'll wait for the night
このままじゃだんだんだめになりそう
At this rate, I'm gradually going to break down
夜を待つよ 夜を待つよ
Waiting for the night, waiting for the night
きっと散々な目にあいそう
I'll surely meet with a terrible fate
夜を待つよ 待つのよ
Waiting for the night, I'm waiting
耐え抜いてざんざん雨に降られて
Enduring it, being pelted by the pouring rain
夜を待つよ 君を待つよ 待つのよ
Waiting for the night, waiting for you, I'm waiting
今は待つのよ
I'm waiting now
濡れたまんま切先を研ぐのよ
While still wet, I'll sharpen the blade
いきあたりばったりにっこり笑って
Going with the flow, smiling brightly
今日もごっこでホットなふりして
Pretending to be hot in a game of make-believe today too
あかさたなさえはまらないよロンリネス
Even the basics don't fit, such loneliness
もののけはあっちでこっちで踊って
Monsters are dancing here and there
Mononoke dancing there and here
君はハッタリばっかりかまして
You are bluffing and bluffing
ぼくは...
I...
夜を待つよ
I wait for the night
このままじゃ
If it stays like this,
どんどんだめになりそう
I'll be ruined more and more
夜を待つよ
I wait for the night
もっと混沌の海が理想
A sea of chaos is more ideal
夜を待つよ
I wait for the night
待つのよ
I'll wait
美しい本当よりもひしゃげた
Rather than the beautiful truth, a twisted version...
夜を待つよ
I wait for the night
君を待つよ
I'll wait for you
待つのよ
I'll wait
今は待つのよ
Now I'll wait
いつかきっときっかけはくるのよ
Someday the trigger will surely come
唇でゆっくりゆっくり騙して
Deceive me slowly, slowly with your lips
ぼくはポップでチープなふりして
I'm pretending to be pop and cheap
真夜中までの夕暮れを泳いでは
Swimming in the sunset until midnight
もののけはうっとりうっそり笑って
Mononoke is smiling enchantingly, deceptively
導火線が燃える中で
While the fuse is burning...
中で今
Now...
嘘をつくの
Tell a lie
夜が来るまでは
Until the night comes
夜が明ける千年前からぼくら
The night dawns, we have been waiting for a thousand years
夜を待つよ
Wait for the night
君がぜんぜんわからないから
Because I don't understand you at all
夜を待つよ
Wait for the night
待つのよ
Wait
無理筋なペンチャン待ちでもいいの
Even if it's an unreasonable penchan waiting
夜を待つよ
Wait for the night
君を待つよ
I'll wait for you
そうよもっと切先を研ぐのよ
Yes, I'll sharpen the blade more
最後最後
Finally, finally
絶対笑うのよ
I'll definitely laugh
君を待つのよ
I'll wait for you
最後最後
Finally, finally
笑うのはぼくらだ
It is us who will laugh
Stellar Stellar
[Title: Stellar Stellar]
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
Stellar Stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure that you've already seen through it all
僕の心の奥で描いた
This script hidden deep down in my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
That I will now read out, acting the part... a clichéd monologue
──ずっと言えない言葉があった
There are so many things I could not say out loud
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
So many walls I could never climb beyond... it never ends
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
Sensing the scent of morning wafting in the air
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
I tried to fight it, filling me with hate
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
I sat in a corner and cried into my knees, trembling all the while
太陽なんていらないから
I don't need the sunshine, don't want it in my life
明けないでいて──
Can dawn please stay away?
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out and make someone feel
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
We're very alike, indeed, both you and me... you're not special, neither am I
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night so Stellar Stellar
ありったけの輝きで
Shining as bright as any eye can take
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
The music will never, ever be stopped tonight
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never...
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
A Cinderella who waits forever
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who goes and gets things done
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
なんて、ありふれた話なんだ
Yeah, right... a run-of-the-mill story, and that's all
理想だけ書き連ねていた
In a diary filled with tales so tall
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
And lying scribbled in the margins, is one of those... this scene so trivial
──きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
I'm sure the stars in the sky are letting tears fall
明日なんて来ないままでいて──
Can tomorrow never come, can it please stay away?
その手を伸ばして
Hold your hand out all the way
誰かに届くように
Reach out and make someone feel
本当に大切なものは
The truly important things in life
目に見えないみたいなんだ
Are painfully invisible to the naked eye
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night so Stellar Stellar
ありのまま考えないで
Just true to myself, make no mistake
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まない
The music can never, ever be stopped tonight
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
あえかなヒロインじゃないさ
Just a damsel in distress forever
救いに行くヒーローだ
But a knight in shining armor
夢見がちなおとぎ話 おとぎ話
It is so fairytale, a total fantasy... A total fantasy
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night so Stellar Stellar
ありったけの輝きで
Shining as bright as any eye can take
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
The music will never, ever be stopped tonight
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through my love so Stellar Stellar
世界、宇宙の真ん中で
In the middle of the world, in the middle of the stars
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まない
The music can never, ever be stopped tonight
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be was never
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
A Cinderella who waits forever
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the prince who goes and gets things done
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
そうだ僕は星だった
Yes, I was a star all along
Stellar Stellar
Midnight Grand Orchestraで「夜を待つよ」
That was "Waiting for Night" by Midnight Grand Orchestra,
そして「Stellar Stellar」でした。
and "Stellar Stellar".
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like them?
そしてイノタクさん、今回のアレンジめっちゃいいですね！
And Inotaku-san, this arrangement is amazing!
いやめちゃくちゃ良かった。
It was really great.
アレンジャーの皆様ありがとうございました。
Thank you to all the arrangers.
ありがとうございました。素晴らしい。
Thank you. It was wonderful.
イノタクさんもギター最高でしたよ。
Inotaku-san, your guitar was awesome too.
いや緊張したわ。はい、ありがとうございました。
Man, I was nervous. But thank you very much.
はい。いつもね、聞いてたあの曲がこんな感じにアレンジされるんだっていうね、
Yeah. Seeing those songs we always hear arranged like this...
あのー、いい意味での裏切りというか、
It's like a twist in a good way,
すごいワクワクするアレンジになっているんじゃないかなと思います。
I think it's a really exciting arrangement.
そしてね、なんかここまでたくさん、この曲たちを歌ってきて、
And you know, having sung these songs so many times up until now,
もう8年やってきたんだなっていうのを改めて実感しましたし、
It's really hit me again that I've been doing this for 8 years now,
これからもね、星街すいせい、そして Midnight Grand Orchestra も、
and from here on, I hope for your continued support for Hoshimachi Suisei
末永くよろしくお願いいたします。
and Midnight Grand Orchestra for a long time to come.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Thank you very much.
ということで、特別ゲストのタク・イノウエさんでした！
And with that, that was our special guest, Taku Inoue!
ありがとうございました。タク・イノウエでした。
Thank you. I'm Taku Inoue.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
さて、楽しい時間はあっという間というところで、
Well, time flies when you're having fun,
次がいよいよ最後の曲になります。
and the next one will finally be the last song.
私自身、この曲が一番アコースティックになったらどうなるんだろうという感じで、
Personally, I was wondering how this song would turn out in an acoustic style,
すごいバンドメンバーさんと合わせるのワクワクしておりました。
so I was really excited to play it with the band members.
皆さんにも楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I hope you all enjoy it too.
それでは、最後に聞いてください。
And now, please listen to the final song.
「ソワレ」。
"Soirée."
あの黄昏も 折り畳めば静寂
The evening is also folded silence.
僕らの街じゃ 暗がりは合図だ
In our city, darkness is the signal.
あの黄昏も
Even if you fold up that twilight,
折り畳めば静寂
it's silence.
僕らの街じゃ
In our town,
暗がりは合図だ
the darkness is a signal.
灯を消して はじめよう
Turn off the lights, let's begin,
幕よ開け
let the curtains rise.
見上げ願いを
Look up and make a wish,
あなたのように変わらず在っていたい
wanting to be exactly as you were.
きらめきのヴェールを目元に
The veil of sparkle on your eyes,
箒星 描いて瞬いた
drawing a shooting star, it twinkled.
ソワレ 今だ!
Soirée! Now!
寝息を立てる太陽の目を盗んで
Stealing eyes from the sleeping sun,
大脱走さ 逃げ出そうぜ
it's a great escape, let's run away.
朝未き空を跨ぐ
Across the morning sky,
栞を挟んだら
if you bookmark it,
行かなくちゃ
you have to go.
ソワレ
Soirée!
夜が明けるまでさ
Until the dawn breaks,
もうすこし
a little longer,
このままで
stay like this.
あの鐘の音は
That bell sound,
茜差したって止まない時間だ
even if it's sunset, is time that doesn't stop.
集まろう
Let's gather,
野望に喝采 エールを
applause for ambition, a cheer...
未来の話を
for the future we speak of.
寂しそうに聞いてる君に誓うよ
I swear to you, who listens so lonely.
世界に魔法がなくたって夢は続いていく
Even if there's no magic in the world, dreams go on.
おやすみに代わるよう
Like replacing "goodnight,"
鳴りやまないメロディー
a melody that never stops,
届けて
deliver it.
見逃すな
Don't miss it.
ソワレ
Soirée!
僕ら目撃者だ
We are witnesses.
蒼穹に手を伸ばした
Reaching out to the blue sky,
水平線がうたた寝したって
even if the horizon dozed off,
とめどなく日々を繋ぐ
endlessly connecting the days,
架け橋 渡ったら
the bridge we crossed.
いつの日か
Someday,
ソワレ
Soirée!
君に届くまでさ
Until it reaches you,
何度でも
again and again,
呼び声を
the call.
消えない軌跡 辿って
Tracing the unerasable trajectory,
幾星霜の果てへ どこまでも
to the end of the ages, no matter where.
一晩じゃ語り尽くせない悲劇も
Even the tragedy that can't be told in one night,
一晩中 語り明かせたら喜劇になってゆく
if we can tell it all night, it becomes a comedy.
聞かせてよ
Let me hear it,
一筋の
a streak of...
瞬いた
Twinkled.
ソワレ 今だ!
Soirée! Now!
寝息を立てる太陽の目を盗んで
Stealing eyes from the sleeping sun,
大脱走さ 逃げ出そうぜ
it's a great escape, let's run away.
朝未き空を跨ぐ
Across the morning sky,
栞を挟んだら
if you bookmark it,
約束だ
it's a promise.
ソワレ
Soirée!
僕が眠るまでは
Until I sleep,
何度でも
again and again,
また明日
see you tomorrow.
拝啓、ソワレ君へ
Dear Soirée-kun,
詠み継がれる僕たちの物語
our story that will be recited.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
以上、星街すいせいでした！
That's all from Hoshimachi Suisei!
本日のカメラ、以上です。お疲れ様です！
That's all for today's cameras. Good work everyone!
お疲れ様でした！
Good work!
谷郷元昭
[Phone: Motoaki Tanigo]
お疲れ様です。配信見てくれてますか？
Hello. Are you watching the stream?
もちろんです。本当にお疲れ様です。
Of course. Truly, good job today.
このあと、あの件発表してきます。
After this, I'm going to announce that matter.
胸を張って、自信を持ってお話ししてきてください。
Stand tall and speak with confidence.
はい。頑張ります！
Yes. I'll do my best!
改めて、8周年記念生誕配信を見てくれて本当にありがとうございます。
Once again, thank you so much for watching my 8th anniversary and birthday stream.
今日は私星街すいせいから皆さんに重大な発表があります。
Today, I, Hoshimachi Suisei, have some major announcements for all of you.
これまで長年、カバーさん、そしてホロライブプロダクションには本当にお世話になってきました。
I've been in the care of Cover Corp and Hololive Production for many years now.
長年の夢だった日本武道館など、たくさんの支えのおかげで夢を一つ一つ叶えていくことができました。
Thanks to all the support, I've been able to fulfill my dreams one by one, including my dream of Budokan.
感謝の気持ちを伝えられる機会がこれまであまりなかったのですが、
I haven't had many chances to express my gratitude until now, but...
谷郷さんをはじめ、ホロライブのタレントのみんな、スタッフの皆さん、関係してくださった皆さんに心の底から感謝をしています。ありがとうございます。
I want to thank Mr. Tanigo, the talents, the staff, and everyone involved from the bottom of my heart. Thank you.
その上で、東京ドームという次の目標に到達するためにはこれからどうすればいいのかを考えてきました。
With that in mind, I've been thinking about what I need to do to reach my next goal: Tokyo Dome.
昔に比べるとたくさんの方に見ていただけるようになりましたが、
Compared to the past, many more people are watching me now, but...
それでもまだまだ越えなければいけない壁がたくさんあります。
there are still many walls I need to overcome.
いろんなものと真剣に向き合い、そして考え抜いた結果、一つの大きな決断を下しました。
After seriously facing various things and thinking it through, I have made a major decision.
びっくりさせちゃうかもしれませんが、その発表を今日この場でさせてください。
It might surprise you, but please allow me to make that announcement right here today.
STUDIO STELLAR
[Visual: STUDIO STELLAR]
星街すいせい 個人事務所設立
[Visual: Hoshimachi Suisei - Establishment of Independent Agency]
ということで、この度星街すいせいは個人事務所を設立することになりました！
And so, I, Hoshimachi Suisei, have established my own independent agency!
名称は、スタジオステラ！
Its name is... Studio Stellar!
今後の私個人の活動、日頃の配信、音楽活動、メディア出演、タイアップ、グッズ展開などなど、全てこのスタジオステラを拠点に行っていくことになります。
My future personal activities, daily streams, music, media appearances, and merchandise will all be centered around Studio Stellar.
と、こんな真面目なトーンで話すと、「え？！すいちゃんホロライブ卒業？！」なんてね、思っちゃう人もいるんじゃないでしょうか。
Talking in such a serious tone... some of you might be thinking, "Wait, is Sui-chan graduating from Hololive?!"
安心してください。ホロライブプロダクションとしての星街すいせいの活動もこれまで通り継続していきます。
Rest assured. My activities as Hoshimachi Suisei of Hololive Production will continue just as before.
ホロライブの大好きなみんなとの活動は引き続き思い切り楽しみつつ、個人としてのさらなる高みを目指す場所がスタジオステラという住み分けです。
I'll continue to fully enjoy activities with my beloved Hololive members, while Studio Stellar will be for reaching even greater heights.
もっともっと大きなステージに立つための前向きで大きな決断なので、ぜひこれからも応援してもらえるとすごくすごく嬉しいです。
This is a positive and major decision made to stand on even bigger stages, so I'd be very happy if you'd continue to support me.
ちなみに、事務所の公式SNSもできましたので、今すぐフォローしてください。IDは、@ST_stellar_infoです。
By the way, the agency's official SNS account is live, so please follow it. The ID is @ST_stellar_info.
この個人事務所設立をきっかけに星街すいせいを構成するあらゆるクリエイティブをリニューアルしていきます。
With this new agency, I'll be renewing all the creative elements that make up Hoshimachi Suisei.
どんどん発表していきますよ。準備はいいですか？
I'll be announcing them one after another. Are you ready?
それでは一つ目。長年愛用してきた星街すいせいのロゴをリニューアルさせていただきました。こちら！
First, I've renewed the Hoshimachi Suisei logo that I've used for many years. Here it is!
これまでのね、歴史とトーンはしっかり踏襲しつつ、今の時代に、そして今の私に一番フィットする形にデザインし直しました。
While maintaining the history and tone, I've redesigned it into a form that best fits the current era and the current me.
さらに！ずっと欲しかった私のシンボルマークもなんと新しく誕生しましたよ。こちら。
Furthermore! My very own symbol mark, which I've wanted for a long time, has finally been created. Here it is.
いかがですか？可愛いね。王冠マークになっております。
What do you think? It's cute, isn't it? It's a crown mark.
お次は、アーティスト写真です。どうぞ！
Next is the artist photo. Here you go!
はい、今回は夜の海で撮影してもらいました。これからの果てしない旅を感じさせるお気に入りの一枚になっております。
Yes, this time I had it taken at the sea at night. It's one of my favorites, giving a sense of the endless journey ahead.
まだまだありますよ。実はこれまでずっとなかったすいちゃんの公式ウェブサイトがついにオープンします！
There's more. Sui-chan's official website, which didn't exist until now, is finally opening!
最新情報だったり、随時アップデートしていくので毎日チェックしてくださいね。
It will be updated with the latest info and more, so please check it every day.
そしてそして、皆さんきっと待望であろう公式ファンクラブも設立が決定しました！
And lastly, the establishment of the official fan club, which I'm sure you've all been waiting for, has been decided!
名前は「星詠み」。みんなの名前を...
The name is "Hoshiyomi". Your name...
星詠み
ファンクラブの名前にさせて頂きました。
[Hoshiyomi]
I've made it the name of my fan club.
これからも、もっとみんなの近くで、
いろんなことを発信していきたいと思っております。
I want to continue reaching out to you all...
from an even closer distance.
ファンクラブ限定グッズが買えたり、
チケットの先行申し込みができたり、
You can buy fan club exclusive merch,
apply for advance tickets,
会報誌、ラジオコンテンツ、などなど
ファンクラブのためにいろいろ準備しているので、
and I'm preparing newsletters, radio content,
and more just for the fan club,
入会をお待ちしております。
so I'll be waiting for you to join.
入会はこの配信終了後21時からです。
Enrollment starts at 21:00
after this stream ends.
ファンクラブができたということは、
次に何が来るかお分かりですよね？
Since we have a fan club now,
I'm sure you know what's coming next, right?
それでは、VTRどうぞ！
So then, let's watch the VTR!
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI ARENA TOUR 2026
"Once Upon a Stellar"
横浜 Kアリーナ横浜
09.08 (Tue) 09.09 (Wed)
[YOKOHAMA: K Arena Yokohama
Sept 8 (Tue) & 9 (Wed)]
神戸 GLION ARENA KOBE
10.21 (Wed)
[KOBE: GLION ARENA KOBE Oct 21 (Wed)]
愛知 IG ARENA
11.07 (Sat)
[AICHI: IG ARENA Nov 7 (Sat)]
福岡 マリンメッセ福岡A館
11.12 (Thu)
[FUKUOKA: MARINE MESSE FUKUOKA Hall A
Nov 12 (Thu)]
本日3月22日 21:00〜
先行抽選受付開始
[Advance lottery applications
start today, March 22nd, at 21:00]
なんと！星街すいせいアリーナツアー、
またしても開催決定！ありがとうございます！
Guess what! Another Hoshimachi Suisei
Arena Tour has been confirmed! Thank you!
タイトルは『Once Upon a Stellar』。
今回は4会場5公演でお届けします。
The title is "Once Upon a Stellar".
This time, I'll be performing 5 shows at 4 venues.
9月8日、9月9日の
Kアリーナ横浜2daysを皮切りに、
Starting with 2 days at K Arena Yokohama
on September 8th and 9th,
10月21日にGLION ARENA KOBE、
11月7日に名古屋IGアリーナ、
then GLION ARENA KOBE on Oct 21st,
IG ARENA Nagoya on Nov 7th,
そして11月12日にマリンメッセ福岡A館。
星街すいせい初となる、4都市アリーナツアー。
and finally Marine Messe Fukuoka Hall A on Nov 12th.
My first-ever 4-city arena tour.
ぜひ遊びに来てください！
Please come and see me!
お気づきの方もいると思うんですが、今回のキービジュアルも
Mika Pikazo先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
As some of you may have noticed, the key visual
was also drawn by Mika Pikazo-sensei!
Mika先生、本当にありがとうございます！
今回も本当に素敵なキービジュアルでね、
Mika-sensei, thank you so much!
It's such a wonderful key visual again,
あの、ぜひたくさん見てください。
so please take a good look.
チケットはなんと、本日の配信終了後から、
早速ファンクラブ先行申し込みがスタートします！
Advance ticket applications through the fan club
start immediately after today's stream!
絶対絶対チェックしてくださいね！
Be sure to check it out!
はい、次！実はもう一つ、
騒がれていたあの大きなプロジェクトが動き出します。
Alright, next! Actually, one more big project
that's been talked about is starting to move.
それでは、VTRをどうぞ！
So then, let's watch the VTR!
再起動
[Title: Restart]
さあ切り裂く静寂 全速前進 生み出す引力で
Now, tear through the silence at full speed,
with the gravity I create
光速のパッセージ アレグロで今日も舞って
A passage at the speed of light,
dancing in allegro again today
わななく轟音 (The) show must go on
A trembling roar, the show must go on
消えない一拍をもっと紡いで
Spinning out more of that inextinguishable beat
打ち鳴らせ今日も万全で！
Striking it out perfectly again today!
描く放物線 ずっと煌めいていけるように
So that the parabola I draw
can keep on sparkling forever
テンポ速めて 最速で到達だ
Picking up the tempo,
I'll reach the top at max speed
しばらく眠っていたあのプロジェクト、
Midnight Grand Orchestraも活動を本格化していきます！
That project that's been dormant,
Midnight Grand Orchestra, is resuming activities!
タイトルは『PROJECT: ALLEGRO』。日程は2027年2月11日、
場所は幕張メッセにてライブを行います。
The title is "PROJECT: ALLEGRO". It'll be held
on Feb 11, 2027, at Makuhari Messe.
こちらも本日からファンクラブで先行申し込みができるので、
ぜひぜひ遊びに来てください。
Advance applications start today for this one too,
so please come and see us.
リリースだったりタイアップなど、
すでに色々決まっているものもありますので、
We already have various things like releases
and tie-ups lined up,
星街すいせい、そしてMidnight Grand Orchestraの
これからを楽しみにしていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you look forward to both
Suisei and Midnight Grand Orchestra's future.
さて、すごい勢いで情報を出していきましたが、
皆さんついてこれておりますか？
Well, I've put out information at an incredible pace,
but are you all keeping up?
今日発表したことは、全部ね、次の大きな目標に向けて、
私が本当に頑張りたいと思って、たくさん悩んだ末の決断です。
Everything I announced today are decisions I've made
after much deliberation towards my next big goal.
環境は少し変わるかもしれないんですが、星街すいせいはもちろん、
これからもずっと私らしくあり続けます。
The environment might change a bit, but I,
Suisei, will continue to be true to myself.
これからもどうか一緒に夢を追いかけてくれると嬉しいです。
よろしくお願いします。
I'd be happy if you'd keep chasing dreams
with me. Thank you.
さて、それでは最後に、3つ。まだ3つもある。
3つだけお知らせをして今日の配信を終わりたいと思います。
Well then, finally, I have three... yes, three more things.
I'll just give you these three announcements and end.
まず一つ目！
First of all!
今日は皆さん、お忘れじゃないですよね？
You haven't forgotten about today, have you?
私の誕生日でもありますということで、
Since it's also my birthday,
生誕グッズをも、もちろんご用意しております！
I have, of course, prepared some birthday merchandise!
Tシャツ、ステッカーセット、アクスタ、
全部入りボックスに加えて、
In addition to the T-shirt, sticker set,
acrylic stand, and "complete box,"
ファンクラブ限定のTシャツなどなど、
there's a fan club exclusive T-shirt, and more...
どれもデザインにこだわりましたので、
ぜひ手に入れてください。
I put a lot of work into the designs,
so please get your hands on them.
二つ目！
Second!
星街すいせいライブツアー2024 スペクトラ・オブ・ノヴァ、
Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 "Spectrum of Nova,"
星街すいせい日本武道館ライブ スーパーノヴァ。
and Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live "Super Nova."
この二つのブルーレイの通常盤が予約受付開始します。
The standard editions of these two Blu-rays
will be available for pre-order.
予約は本日22時からスタートです。
Pre-orders start today at 10:00 PM.
今回のブルーレイは、以前のようなセット販売はなく、
This time, there won't be a set sale like before.
ツアー、武道館、それぞれ個別での販売のみになります。
The tour and Budokan concerts
will only be sold separately.
そしてツアーのブルーレイは、
埼玉公演のみの映像化となっています。
And the tour Blu-ray only features
the Saitama performance.
ただし、特典映像として、他のツアー公演の楽曲も
一部収録されております。
However, some songs from other tour dates
are included as bonus footage.
ゲストパートとか。
Like the guest parts.
何が収録されているかはぜひ、
ブルーレイでチェックしてみてください。
Please check the Blu-ray to see
exactly what's included.
なお、今回は去年販売したブルーレイとは
仕様が少し異なり、
Also, the specifications this time are slightly
different from last year's Blu-ray,
ツアーブルーレイの特典映像以外の特典は
付属していませんのでご注意ください。
so please note that no bonuses other than the
bonus footage are included on the tour Blu-ray.
ただ、その分ね、お買い求めやすい価格になっておりますので、
However, the price is more affordable because of that,
詳しくは特設サイトや、公式X、公式Twitterを
チェックしてください。
so please check the special site or official X
(Twitter) for details.
そして、三つ目！
And thirdly!
皆さん、お待たせしました！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
毎年恒例ですが、新曲が出ます！
As is our annual tradition, a new song is coming out!
タイトルは、『プリマドンナ』。
The title is "Primadonna."
この配信が終わった後、21時半から
ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開が始まります。
The music video premiere starts at 9:30 PM
after this stream ends.
これからの星街すいせいの名刺代わりになるような、
It's a high-energy track that'll serve as
すごくテンションが上がる曲に仕上がっております。
a new introduction for Hoshimachi Suisei.
概要欄に貼ってるURLから飛べるので、
ぜひ楽しみに待っててください。
You can find the URL in the description,
so please look forward to it.
絶対に待機していてください！
Make sure to be there for the premiere!
ということで、
With that said,
以上で星街すいせい8周年記念生誕配信を終わります。
that concludes Hoshimachi Suisei's 8th anniversary
and birthday stream.
今日は本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for today.
新しいスタジオステラの星街すいせいも、
どうかどうか、よろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support Hoshimachi Suisei
here at Studio Stellar.
それでは、またねー！
See you again!
最後までみてくれてありがとう☆
これからも私は私らしく、みんなと共にあります。
[Message] Thank you for watching until the end! ☆
From now on, I'll stay true to myself, together with everyone.
新しい挑戦を続けて、まだ見ぬ世界を見に行こう！
- Suisei
Let's keep taking on new challenges
and go see worlds we haven't seen yet! - Suisei
最後までみてくれてありがとう☆
Thank you for watching until the end! ☆
これからも私は私らしく、みんなと共にあります。
From now on, I'll stay true to myself
and stay together with all of you.
新しい挑戦を続けて、また見ぬ世界を見に行こう!
I'll keep taking on new challenges,
so let's go see worlds we've never seen before!